Thomas Chang

(718) 640-0135 / tomchang93@gmail.com www.thomaschang.io / thomaschangusa / thomaschang7

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A highly motivated and creative Software Engineer with experience in developing novel applications through an Apprenticeship at Microsoft and an intensive Dev Bootcamp. Demonstrates knowledge of programming, testing, and algorithms and is experienced in optimizing code for stability and functionality. Applies an analytical approach to solving problems, collaborates effectively in team settings, and communicates concisely at all levels.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Application Development
- Project Management
- Research & Analysis
- Full Stack Development
- Coding & Programming
- Debugging & Testing
- Front End Development
- Content Development
- Team Collaboration

Programming: JavaScript, SQL, Git, C#, Visual Studio, Agile, React, GraphQL, HTML5, CSS3, Node, Ruby on Rails

WORK EXPERIENCE

MICROSOFT - Redmond, WA

Jul 2017 - Nov 2017

Software Engineer Apprentice

- Selected as one of 30 from a pool of 500 to 600 to undertake an apprenticeship comprising five weeks of lectures presented by a Senior Microsoft Engineer and 10 weeks of practical work on the Microsoft Dynamics 365 platform.
- Created and automated test cases and ensured product stability by conducting smoke, sanity, and regression tests.

PROFESSIONAL PHYSICAL THERAPY - New York, NY

Jan 2016 - Feb 2017

Physical Therapy Aide

- Analyzed data on patient progress during treatment and prepared reports for presentation to the Physical Therapist.
- Adapted to different situations with ease and communicated effectively with patients, visitors, and staff.

ABSOLUTE PERFORMANCE - Buffalo, NY

Jan 2015 - Apr 2015

Strength & Conditioning Intern

- Worked with a team to launch a Strength Fights Cancer benefit event, which attracted over 150 local competitors and secured sponsorships from companies such as FitAID, Geico, and Hammerhead.
- Promoted a training environment that encouraged collaboration, discipline and healthy competition.

PROJECTS

LEAP Website

• Collaborated with the Program Manager, Designer, Developers and stakeholder to develop consumer-facing content, which increased visibility and drove internet traffic to the Microsoft LEAP website.

DJ Mood

• Created an application that uses facial recognition technologies to capture human emotions and designed an algorithm to curate a playlist on Spotify, and used APIs such as Kairos, Last.FM, and Spotify.

Launchpad

Developed a digital simulation of a Launchpad, an 8 x 8 grid of buttons for playing music.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

THE PRACTICE WORLDWIDE - New York, NY Oct 2015 - Jul 2016

Music Production Intern

Assisted the Production Team and converted archived cassette tapes into a digital format using Digital Performer.

EDUCATION

DEV BOOTCAMP – New York, NY

2017

Software Development

Intensive 18-week program to learn web development and enable agile collaboration, teamwork and leadership.

STATE UNIVERSITY OF NEW YORK AT BUFFALO - Buffalo, NY

2015